Julio Valerio

New York, New York, United States



jvjvalerio@me.com



linkedin.com/in/julio-valerio-779a3181

Summary

Curious and motivated engineer with interests ranging from decentralized ledger technologies, product development, software engineering, and IT Support with over 15 years of experience. Currently pursuing a bachelors degree in Computer Science with the goal of building impactful solutions.

Experience

I.T. Associate Level 1

City University of New York-College of Staten Island

Oct 2017 - Present (3 years 9 months +)

- -Supervised and provided professional development and establishing work schedules for the technical support unit staff.
- -Provided support to end-users including: identifying, researching and resolving technical problems, and responding to support requests made via telephone calls, e-mails, and the self-service portal.
- -Utilized Bomgar desktop software to support remote control, desktop sharing and file transfer to offsite users.
- -Communicated with technology users and staff to understand, identify, document, and resolve problems.
- -Installed approved software releases, system upgrades, patches, and software related compatibility issues.
- -Maintained, analyzed, troubleshoot, and repaired computer systems, repaired and replaced components in laptops, desktops, printers, and other peripherals.
- -Evaluated, prioritized, and provided support for incoming requests for assistance from end-users experiencing problems with hardware, software, networking, and other IT-related issues.
- -Documented incidents in the KACE ticketing system and ensured timely resolution of open tickets.
- -Maintained classroom SMARTBoard technology to include software updates and general maintenance needs.
- -Managed conference calls and video conferencing software and peripherals. Assisted users with teleconferencing software such as Zoom, Citrix, and Polycom technologies.
- -Created, updated, and managed user permissions and computer and group assignments in Active Directory.
- -Monitored system wide difficulties and worked with the Office of Information Technology team and other support staff in providing timely notification of problem occurrence, updates, and resolution to appropriate groups, as required.
- -Maintained a working knowledge of computer technology, network systems, and standard software and act as a resource of technical information to the end user community.

Google's Mentorship and Development Program

Google

Nov 2020 - May 2021 (7 months)

Participated in Google's CSSI: Online Program - a 2-week intensive introductory project-based

python processing curriculum taught by Google engineers

- Completed 10 individual coding projects by using concepts such as variables, conditionals, loops and functions
- Participated in a 1:1 mentorship program with Google Engineers to develop personal and professional goals over a 6 month period

💹 IT Support Assistant

LaGuardia Community College

Oct 2013 - Sep 2017 (4 years)

- -Communicated with technology users and other technology staff to understand the details of work assignments and the nature of problems and logged problem reports.
- -Tested computer and communications equipment to check its capacity and capability to perform as specified, and reported findings.
- -Identified problems regarding computer, peripheral, or communications equipment, and other operating environment.
- -Determined the cause of malfunctions and various methods (e.g. observation, use of diagnostic software or equipment).
- -Informed supervisor or designated contact for repairs and followed up to assure problems have been resolved.
- -Performed simple repairs such as replacing faulty computers, peripherals, and communications equipment and/or component parts.
- -Assisted in orientation and training of new staff. Temporarily supervised other personnel.
- -Assisted with data storage operations, Transferred data from one medium/format to another and performed routine back up and recovery tasks.
- -As directed made minor adjustments and implemented routine technical updates to hardware and software (including networks, operating systems, and applications software.

ട്ടെ Geek Squad

Best Buy

Jun 2009 - Aug 2012 (3 years 3 months)

- Helped drive a positive customer experience by building relationships, exhibiting empathy, and providing solutions for their needs.
- Provided positive, timely engagements with customers during the check-in and check-out process.
- Understood customer's technology issues by asking probing questions, listening, asking clarifying questions, taking detailed notes, and providing accurate time estimates for next steps.
- Monitored queues and providing accurate status updates to customers.
- Clearly communicated and partnered with team members.

IT Support Specialist

Gotham City Mortgage

May 2004 - Jun 2009 (5 years 2 months)

- -Maintained a predictive dialing system for the telemarketing team.
- -Was the sole IT Technician for the office of 30 employees comprised of loan officers, a telemarketing team, and underwriters.
- -Assisted in the setup and installation of VOIP systems.

-Maintained, analyzed, troubleshot, and repaired computer systems, repaired or replaced components in laptops, desktops, printers, and other peripherals.

Education

RC Brooklyn College

Computer Science 2021 - 2022

🙎 LaGuardia Community College

Associate of Arts and Sciences - AAS, Computer Network Administrations & Security 2018 - 2020

Aviation Career And Technical High School

High School Diploma, Aeronautics/Aviation/Aerospace Science and Technology, General 2000 - 2005

Licenses & Certifications

- ★ Apple Certified Associate Mac Integration 10.13 Apple
- BTA Certified Blockchain Business Foundations Blockchain Training Alliance Issued Feb 2020 Expires Feb 2022

 0xb4e70cadc4ea21abe54858bcf87776900f5f1545abf2c2d71341f6d476092496
- Certified ScrumMaster (CSM) Scrum Alliance Issued Feb 2020 - Expires Feb 2022 1191372
- G Google IT Support Professional Certificate Google
- Blockchain Essentials ConsenSys Academy Issued May 2020 - Expires May 2022 f653-7601-6236-9403

Skills

Computer Hardware Troubleshooting • Remote Troubleshooting • Network Troubleshooting • Customer Service • Operating Systems • Help Desk Support • Email • Data Entry • Conferences • Connectivity